Benjamin Karlsson

Senior Fullstack developer

Software development Skills

Typescript, ReactJs, Storybook, Jest, Cypress.io, Redux, hooks, EmotionJs, Design Systems, Mono repo tools, Git, Jira, Rest, Graphql

Other skills - Azure DevOps, Design thinking, Adobe, Illustrator, Davinci Resolve, Sketch,

Summary

Frontend developer with industry experience building large-scale web applications and design systems. I'm specialized in TypeScript and have professional experience skills working autonomous with React, its patterns and architecture like hooks, redux and routing. Dedicated to developing and optimize beautiful, user-friendly, and feature-rich tested websites. Health & training junky with a passion for creation.

Experience

Senior Fullstack Developer @Follow your commit - EcarX | Sep 2021 - current

Visualizing internal the CI/CD system by building a React web application. Allowing you to see a piece of code go through pipelines and tests on physical hardware all the way to the car. Integration to Gitlab, Jira Software and other internal endpoints. Benjamin worked fully autonomous together with a BE developer. He has responsibility over the user experience and design using modern web development practices.

Typescript, React, Golang, Kubernetes, Docker, PostgreSQL, Vercel SWR, React Hooks Pattern, HTML, CSS, Mantine, Jest, Cypress, Storybook, GitLab, Jira, REST & GraphQL, Microsoft Active Directory, OAuth,

Senior Web Engineer @Digital Trials - Astra Zeneca | Apr 2019 – Juli 2021

Benjamin worked in a big team with senior developers from the start of the project. Developing a react web application with modern and responsive css. Integrated with CMS, IDP, and rest APIs and maintaining an extensive UI/component library. The project set extremely high requirements for testing and security

Typescript, React, Redux, React Hooks pattern, HTML, CSS, MonoRepo (Nx & Lerna), Jest, Styled Components, Storybook, Git, Jira

Frontend Developer @Scope360 | Feb 2020 - Apr 2020

Work consisted of increasing the usability and development of new features in the tool, As well as moving legacy Angular code into a Vuejs application.

MonoRepo(Lerna), Storybook, VueJs, AngularJs, Javascript, Chrome Extensions

Design System Engineer @SKF | Apr 2019 – Jan 2020

Worked with designers building a components library and Design system consumed globally to deliver a consistent brand experience at scale for SKF. Used by developers in more than 3 continents.

- Researching and developing React components with a focus on developer experience.
- Architecting CSS framework with Atomic CSS, reducing styling variables by 95%. Increasing styling efficiency, ramp up time with a single source of truth,
- Creating Accessible components like, Buttons, multi select dropdown inputs, virtualized lists and Draggable lists.
- Refactoring and reviewing code.

MonoRepo (Lerna), Storybook, TailwindCSS, AtomicCss, React, Javascript, Azure DevOps, Scrum, Design System

Frontend Developer @SKF | Feb 2018 - Apr 2019

My role was to develop the UI of a reporting and analytics tool for monitoring health and data of ball bearing.

- Write and style front-end components that met the requirements of our mocks and fulfilled user stories.
- Exploring layout possibilities
- Hosted daily exercise after the morning stand-up, teaching more than 70ppl how to do "the Floss".

ReactJs, Redux, JavaScript, Lerna (monorepo), SASS(CSS), HTML, TailwindCSS, BlueprintJS, Cypress. Azure Devops, GIT

UX / UI Developer @RISE Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

Working on the EU funded science project Sea Traffic Management (STM), a way to streamline the port traffic. Tight feedback loop with stakeholders creating mockups and implementation and gathering user statistics.

UX / UI Developer @Coboom | Sep 2017-08 - Dec 2017

Participated in a joint venture to conceptualize and develop the innovation project Coboom. A platform for students and companies with the purpose to integrate and accelerate innovation and remove barriers between students and companies.

Innovator @**OpenHack** - Coding for humanity | Sep 2017

My team won the title "Best social/Humanitarian impact" at the Open source hackathon OpenHack Coding for Humanity 2017 in Gothenburg. Main role was conceptualization, prototyping with interactive mockups and pitching for the jury.

Education

2014 - 2017 **Bachelor's in informatics** - Design, Innovation & Interaction Umeå University

Language

Swedish: Native expertiseEnglish: Fluent expertiseGerman: Conversational

Contacts

• **Phone:** (+46) 073 182 86 65

Email: hej@benjaminkarlsson.comLinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/benjik

• **GitHub**: github.com/B3Kay

• Location: Fulltime Remote with Flexibility